Register of the Institute of Economic Affairs (Great Britain) records
Hoover Institution Archives
Institute of Economic Affairs (Great Britain) Records,
1940-2010
96026
Hoover Institution Archives
510 manuscript boxes, 23 oversize boxes, 1 cassette box, 14 motion picture film reels (239 linear feet)
Correspondence, minutes, press releases, financial records, conference proceedings, drafts and printed copies of publications, other printed matter, and photographs relating to laissez-faire economic theory and associated concepts of liberty, and to analysis of British and international economic policy. Includes personal papers of some members.
Institute of Economic Affairs (Great Britain)
Access
Boxes 268-269 and 3 folders in Box 270 closed. The remainder of the collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
Established in 1955 by the late Sir Antony Fisher, the Institute of Economic Affairs is a research and educational trust, independent of any political party or group, and financed by sales of publications, conference fees, and donations.
Its mission is to improve understanding of the fundamental institutions of a free society, with particular reference to the role of markets in solving economic and social problems. The Institute pursues its mission by organizing conferences, seminars, and lectures on a range of subjects; reaching out to school and college students; brokering media introductions and appearances; and, most of all, by maintaining a regular publishing program. In addition to its main series of publications, the Institute also publishes a quarterly journal, Economic Affairs, and has three specialist units, the Health and Welfare Unit, the Environment Unit, and the Education and Training Unit.
In his book on the history of the Institute, Richard Cockett wrote: "the IEA thus sought, through its publications programme, to demonstrate the efficacy of economic liberalism and to apply the principles of the free market to all areas of economic activity." The impact of the Institute on British politics was best summarized by Milton Friedman, who remarked that "without the IEA, I doubt very much whether there would have been a Thatcherite revolution."
Two of the Institute's most prominent advocates and contributors were Friedrich A. von Hayek (Antony Fisher's main inspiration) and fellow Nobel laureate Milton Friedman, both of whom deposited their papers in the Hoover Archives. Other economists of international renown who have done so include Gottfried Haberler, Fritz Machlup, Schmölders, Gordon Tullock, and F. A. Harper, who invited Fisher to the United States in 1952 and whose Foundation for Economic Education gave him the model for the future IEA. Other related collections are those of philosopher Karl Popper, publisher Henry Regnery, and journalist Lawrence Fertig. Many of these figures were also members of the Mont Pèlerin Society, an organization of laissez-faire economists whose records we house as well.
Scope and Content
The records of the IEA were accessioned in the Hoover Institution Archives as a deposit in 1996. Most of the materials date from the 1970s, with the notable exception of the press cuttings, which go back to 1940; the financial records, which have been kept since the Institute's founding; and the publications file, which starts in 1961 and will be regularly brought up to date.
The latter is one of the largest series in the collection, and consists not only of printed copies (from books to pamphlets, occasional papers, and research monographs) but also of correspondence with authors, agents, and publishers, and of manuscripts (for many of those that were eventually published, related comments by reviewers, galleys, and other materials are also included).
Other records of note are those in the series dedicated to the Institute's journal Economic Affairs, which contains interesting correspondence with authors.
The personal files of several prominent IEA members are also represented in this collection. Particularly extensive are the papers of Lord Ralph Harris, the Institute's first director, and Arthur Seldon, its first editorial director. In the words of Cockett, "The duo of Harris and Seldon effectively ran the IEA from 1957 until the mid-1980s."
Since the accession of the collection in 1996, the Hoover Institution Archives has received many increments to the IEA records. The Incremental Materials are arranged in twenty subseries that mirror the organization of the original accession. Although filed separately, many of these materials belong to the same categories of records. For all series present in the original accession, please check the Incremental Materials for additional documents.
In addition, the Incremental Materials contain the correspondence and working files of John Blundell, who became general director of the IEA in 1993. Blundell also served as president of the Atlas Network and the Institute for Humane Studies. Documents related to these groups, as well as the Mont Pelerin Society, can be found in the Incremental Materials.
The Incremental Materials contain a substantial amount of audiovisual materials, including video and sound recordings of IEA members, and recordings from the Mont Pelerin Society Aviemore Conference.
The Incremental Materials of 2014 include the papers of Barbara Shenfield, as well as files related to the IEA's journal Economic Affairs.
Audiotapes.; Economic policy.; Economists.; Free enterprise.; Great Britain--Economic policy--1945-1964.; Liberty.; Motion pictures.; Video tapes.
- Conference, Seminar, and Lecture File, 1980-1995
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, proceedings, publicity materials, photographs, and miscellany regarding events held at the IEA, arranged numerically by filing number, then chronologically. See also Incremental Materials.
  - Arranged numerically (by filing number)
    - 04/2/1 (1987 April 7)-04/2/4 (1987 October 1) (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
    - 04/2/5 (1987 October 21)-04/2/8 [1] (1988 January 7) (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
    - 04/2/8 [2] (1988 January 7)-04/2/12 [1] (1988 June 9) (Box 3, Folder 1-7)
    - 04/2/12 [2] (1988 June 9)-04/2/16 (1988 December 8) (Box 4, Folder 1-6)
    - 04/2/17 (1988 May 18)-04/2/21 (1989 May 16) (Box 5, Folder 1-6)
    - 04/2/22 [1] (1989 May 17)-04/2/26 [1] (1990 January 9) (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
    - 04/2/26 [2] (1990 January 9)-04/2/30 (1990 March 31) (Box 7, Folder 1-6)
    - 04/2/31 (1991)-04/2/39 (1990 April 19) (Box 8, Folder 1-11)
    - 04/2/40 (1990 April 19)-04/2/55 (1991 January 15) (Box 9, Folder 1-16)
    - 04/2/56 (1991 January 15)-04/2/69 (1992 January 14) (Box 10, Folder 1-14)
    - 04/2/70 (1992 January 14)-04/2/80 [1] (1993 January 21) (Box 11, Folder 1-11)
    - 04/2/80 [2] (1993 January 21)-04/2/89 (1994 October 20) (Box 12, Folder 1-7)
    - 05/1 [1] (1988 July 21-05/7 [1] (1990 July 2) (Box 13, Folder 1-8)
    - 05/7 [2] (1990 July 2)-05/12 [2] (1991 March 25) (Box 14, Folder 1-8)
    - 05/13 (1991 March 25)-05/19 [2] (1991 July 4) (Box 15, Folder 1-8)
    - 05/20 (1991 July 4)-05/26 (1991 December 12) (Box 16, Folder 1-8)
    - 05/27 (1991 December 12)-05/29 [3] (1992 July 1) (Box 17, Folder 1-5)
    - 05/30 (1992 July 1)-05/37 (1995 May 23) (Box 18, Folder 1-8)
  - Arranged chronologically (Box 19)
    - Undated (Folder 1)
    - 1980 June 4 - 1988 June 9 (Folder 2-10)
    - 1989 May 17 - 1990 April 19 (Box 20, Folder 1-4)
- Correspondence, 1975-1991
  General correspondence arranged alphabetically within chronological groupings.
  - 1975-1982 (Box 21)
    - A - Com (Folder 1-6)
    - Con - Gol (Box 22, Folder 1-7)
    - Goo - J (Box 23, Folder 1-7)
    - K - Pep (Box 24, Folder 1-8)
    - Pen - Sm (Box 25, Folder 1-6)
    - Sn - Z (Box 26, Folder 1-9)
  - 1983-1986 (Box 27)
    - A - D (Folder 1-6)
    - E - M (Box 28, Folder 1-10)
    - N - V (Box 29, Folder 1-8)
    - W - Z (Box 30, Folder 1-9)
  - 1989-1991
    - A - G
    - H - P (Box 31, Folder 1-10)
    - R - Z (Box 32, Folder 1-7)
- Economic Affairs File, 1978-1997
  Accounts, agendas, agreements, articles, budgets, contracts, correspondence, memoranda, minutes, press releases, printed matter, and reports relating to the journal published by the IEA starting in 1979, arranged alphabetically by physical form. See also Incremental Materials. Originally published as The Journal of Economic Affairs.
  - Agreements and contracts, Includes correspondence, 1980-1990 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Articles and editorial material. Includes correspondence, indexes, and memoranda
    - 1982-1986 (Folder 2)
    - 1987-1988 (Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1993
    - General
      - Unidentified (Folder 4)
      - A (Folder 5)
      - Ba-Bh (Folder 6)
      - Bi-Bu (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Ca-Ch (Folder 2)
      - Ci-Cu (Folder 3)
      - D (Folder 4)
      - E (Folder 5)
      - F (Folder 6)
      - G (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Ha-Hi (Folder 2)
      - Ho-Hy (Folder 3)
      - I (Folder 4)
      - J (Folder 5)
      - K (Folder 6)
      - La-Li (Folder 7)
      - Ll-Ly (Folder 8)
      - Ma-Me (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Mi-Mu (Folder 2)
      - N (Folder 3)
      - O (Folder 4)
      - P (Folder 5)
      - Q (Folder 6)
      - R (Folder 7)
      - Sa-Sh (Folder 8)
      - Si-Sy (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - T (Folder 2)
      - U (Folder 3)
      - V (Folder 4)
      - W (Folder 5)
      - Y (Folder 6)
      - Z (Folder 7)
    - Addison, John T., 1987-1991 (Folder 8)
    - Allen, G. C., 1980-1982 (Folder 9)
    - Alsop, D. J., 1982-1986 (Folder 10)
    - Anthony, Vivian, 1985-1989 (Folder 11)
    - Apostolakis, Bobby, 1986 (Folder 12)
    - Aronson, Richard, 1981-1982 (Folder 13)
    - Aschheim, Joseph, 1981-1982 (Folder 14)
    - Ash, Colin, 1989 (Folder 15)
    - Ashford, Nigel, 1984-1988 (Folder 16)
    - Atkinson, Rodney, 1981-1990 (Folder 17)
    - Audley, Bernard, 1982-1983 (Folder 18)
    - Badelt, Christoph, 1981-1985 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Baird, Charles, 1984-1985 (Folder 2)
    - Baker, James, 1986 (Folder 3)
    - Baker, Stephen, 1980-1982 (Folder 4)
    - Bannock, Graham, 1985-1991 (Folder 5)
    - Barrett, Sean, 1987-1989 (Folder 6)
    - Barnett, Lord, 1986-1990 (Folder 7)
    - Barry, Norman, 1983-1991 (Folder 8)
    - Basil Blackwell Publisher Ltd.
      - 1979 (Folder 9)
      - 1980 (Folder 10)
      - 1981 (Folder 11)
      - 1982 (Folder 12)
      - 1983-1984 (Folder 13)
    - Batchelor, Roy, 1980-1988 (Folder 14)
    - Bauer, Peter, 1979-1991 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Bazen, Stephen, 1991 (Folder 2)
    - Beckman, Robert, 1984-1986 (Folder 3)
    - Beenstock, Michael, 1980-1988 (Folder 4)
    - Beesley, Michael, 1979-1989 (Folder 5)
    - Beladi, Hamid, 1986 (Folder 6)
    - Belgrano, Eduardo, 1988-1991 (Folder 7)
    - Bellak, J. G., 1984-1985 (Folder 8)
    - Benegas Lynch, Alberto, 1984-1985 (Folder 9)
    - Berens, David, 1986-1988 (Folder 10)
    - Bergstrom, A. R., 1984-1985 (Folder 11)
    - Best, Minkie, 1989-1990 (Folder 12)
    - Beverley, K., 1991 (Folder 13)
    - Blaug, Mark, 1980-1988 (Folder 14)
    - Blight, Catherine, 1983-1989 (Folder 15)
    - Block, Walter, 1981-1990 (Folder 16)
    - Blundell, John, 1982-1991 (Folder 17)
    - Boaz, David, 1988-1991 (Folder 18)
    - Bolivar, Carolina R. de, 1983-1988 (Folder 19)
    - Bomhoff, Eduard, 1984 (Folder 20)
    - Booth, Philip, 1984 (Folder 21)
    - Bootle, Roger, 1991 (Folder 22)
    - Bosanquet, Nicholas, 1983-1985 (Folder 23)
    - Botsford, David, 1985-1988 (Folder 24)
    - Bouckaert, Boudewijn, 1983-1988 (Folder 25)
    - Bourlet, Jim, 1989 (Folder 26)
    - Bovard, James, 1988-1989 (Folder 27)
    - Bracewell-Milnes, J. B., 1980-1991 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Bright, Christopher, 1991 (Folder 2)
    - Brittan, Samuel, 1979-1985 (Folder 3)
    - Bruce-Gardyne, Lord, 1984-1985 (Folder 4)
    - Brunner, Karl, 1980-1985 (Folder 5)
    - Buchanan, Jim, 1979-1982 (Folder 6)
    - Budd, Alan, 1979-1990 (Folder 7)
    - Burgess, Ronald, 1982-1983 (Folder 8)
    - Burn, Duncan, 1979-1981 (Folder 9)
    - Burnet, Alastair, Sir, 1983-1986 (Folder 10)
    - Burroughes, Tom, 1987-1988 (Folder 11)
    - Burton, John, 1978-1991 (Folder 12)
    - Butler, David, 1986-1990 (Folder 13)
    - Butterworth and Co., 1978-1983 (Folder 14)
    - Capie, Forrest, 1983-1991 (Folder 15)
    - Casson, Mark, 1984-1990 (Folder 16)
    - Castorina, Camille, 1983-1984 (Folder 17)
    - Castro, José, 1984-1985 (Folder 18)
    - Chacko, V. I., 1987 (Folder 19)
    - Chalk, Andrew, 1987-1988 (Folder 20)
    - Chapple, Frank, 1980-1984 (Folder 21)
    - Chen, Sun, 1980-1984 (Folder 22)
    - Cheung, Steven, 1984-1991 (Folder 23)
    - Chiplin, Brian, 1980-1991 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Chown, John, 1984-1985 (Folder 2)
    - Christopher, Tony, 1981-1984 (Folder 3)
    - Chrystal, Alec, 1987-1991 (Folder 4)
    - City Publications
      - 1987-1988 (Folder 5)
      - 1989 (Folder 6)
      - 1990 (Folder 7)
      - 1991 (Folder 8)
      - 1992 (Folder 9)
      - 1993 (Folder 10)
    - Clark, Colin, 1981-1988 (Folder 11)
    - Clark, Simon, 1987 (Folder 12)
    - Clarke, Peter, 1981-1990 (Folder 13)
    - Coleman, David, 1987-1991 (Folder 14)
    - Congdon, Tim, 1982-1988 (Folder 15)
    - Cook, Mark, 1990-1991 (Folder 16)
    - Coolican, Angela, 1983-1984 (Folder 17)
    - Copeland, Laurence, 1986-1990 (Folder 18)
    - Corbet, Hugh, 1986-1989 (Folder 19)
    - Corfield, Frederick, Sir, 1981-1982 (Folder 20)
    - Cowen, Tyler, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Craven, Barry, 1987-1991 (Folder 2)
    - Csikos-Nagy, Béla, 1980-1986 (Folder 3)
    - Culp, Christopher, 1989-1990 (Folder 4)
    - Culyer, A. J., 1983-1984 (Folder 5)
    - Curwen, Peter, 1985-1986 (Folder 6)
    - Darby, Michael, 1982-1986 (Folder 7)
    - Davies, Christie, 1989-1991 (Folder 8)
    - Davies, Stephen, 1983-1987 (Folder 9)
    - Davis, E. W., 1984-1985 (Folder 10)
    - Dawson, Graham, 1980-1990 (Folder 11)
    - Denman, Donald, 1982-1989 (Folder 12)
    - Dennison, S. R., 1981-1985 (Folder 13)
    - Dmitriev, Michael, 1989-1991 (Folder 14)
    - Dorrell, Stephen, 1983-1984 (Folder 15)
    - Dowd, Kevin, 1986-1991 (Folder 16)
    - Earl, Peter, 1983-1984 (Folder 17)
    - Eaton, Jack, 1984-1988 (Folder 18)
    - Efron, Edith, 1985 (Folder 19)
    - Eggerston, Thraín, 1983-1985 (Folder 20)
    - Elkan, Walter, 1979-1986 (Folder 21)
    - Ellig, Jerry, 1985-1987 (Folder 22)
    - Elliott, Nicholas, 1987-1991 (Folder 23)
    - Eltis, Walter, 1979-1990 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Empoli, Domenico da, 1980 (Folder 2)
    - Engels, Wolfram, 1982-1985 (Folder 3)
    - England, Catherine, 1983-1984 (Folder 4)
    - Eusepi, Giuseppe, 1986-1988 (Folder 5)
    - Fand, David, 1984-1987 (Folder 6)
    - Farsio, Farzad, 1991 (Folder 7)
    - Feige, Edgar, 1980-1982 (Folder 8)
    - Fergenson, P. Everett, 1987-1988 (Folder 9)
    - Ferns, H. S., 1979-1989 (Folder 10)
    - Fisher, Michael, 1985-1991 (Folder 11)
    - Fletcher, Ray, 1981-1988 (Folder 12)
    - Flew, Antony, 1981-1991 (Folder 13)
    - Foley, Bernard, 1984-1985 (Folder 14)
    - Folkes, D. E., 1982-1989 (Folder 15)
    - Forrest, David, 1981-1982 (Folder 16)
    - Foster, C. D., 1985 (Folder 17)
    - Fowler, Ronald, 1980 (Folder 18)
    - Frankel, S. H., 1979-1981 (Folder 19)
    - Fredborg, Arvid, 1983-1984 (Folder 20)
    - Freeman, D. A., 1981-1988 (Folder 21)
    - Frey, Bruno, 1982-1983 (Folder 22)
    - Friedman, Milton, 1983-1988 (Folder 23)
    - Fry, Maxwell, 1991 (Folder 24)
    - Gardner, John, 1989-1990 (Folder 25)
    - Garwood-Scott, Ruth, 1983-1984 (Folder 26)
    - Gash, Norman, 1979-1983 (Folder 27)
    - Gay, David, 1980-1984 (Folder 28)
    - Genn-Bash, Angela, 1984-1985 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Gergils, Hakan, 1989 (Folder 2)
    - Gibson, Norman, 1979-1981 (Folder 3)
    - Giersch, Herbert, 1982-1985 (Folder 4)
    - Gilbreath, Kent, 1986 (Folder 5)
    - Gillibrand, Maurice, 1991 (Folder 6)
    - Gissurarson, Hans, 1983-1985 (Folder 7)
    - Goldsmith, Walter, 1989 (Folder 8)
    - Goldstein, Alfred, 1986 (Folder 9)
    - Goodheart, Charles, 1984-1991 (Folder 10)
    - Goodwin, P. B., 1989-1990 (Folder 11)
    - Gordon, Peter, 1984-1986 (Folder 12)
    - Gorman, Teresa, 1986-1990 (Folder 13)
    - Goss, Richard, 1986 (Folder 14)
    - Gould, Julius, 1980-1983 (Folder 15)
    - Grant, Rob, 1981-1982 (Folder 16)
    - Gray, John, 1979-1984 (Folder 17)
    - Green, David, 1983-1986 (Folder 18)
    - Green, Diana, 1981-1984 (Folder 19)
    - Greenaway, David, 1979-1991 (Folder 20)
    - Gregory, Roy, 1983-1984 (Folder 21)
    - Grimond, Lord, 1981-1986 (Folder 22)
    - Gumpert, Hannes, 1985 (Folder 23)
    - Hagedorn, Konrad, 1983-1986 (Folder 24)
    - Haggman, Bertil, 1983-1984 (Folder 25)
    - Hague, D. C., 1981-1982 (Folder 26)
    - Hall, Stuart, 1984-1985 (Folder 27)
    - Hallet, Graham, 1980-1984 (Folder 28)
    - Hamilton, Neil, 1983-1984 (Folder 29)
    - Hanke, Steve, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Hankins, 1983-1984 (Folder 2)
    - Hanson, Charles, 1979-1989 (Folder 3)
    - Hardie, Alexandra, 1982-1991 (Folder 4)
    - Harris, Lord, 1989-1991 (Folder 5)
    - Hartley, Keith, 1989-1991 (Folder 6)
    - Harvey, Douglas, 1984 (Folder 7)
    - Hawkins, Quentin, 1989-1990 (Folder 8)
    - Healey, Nigel, 1989-1991 (Folder 9)
    - Hemsted, John, 1987-1988 (Folder 10)
    - Hibbs, John, 1980-1991 (Folder 11)
    - High, Hugh, 1987-1991 (Folder 12)
    - Hildreth, Jan, 1982 (Folder 13)
    - Hill, Malcom, 1983-1984 (Folder 14)
    - Hoff, Ole-Jacob, 1981-1983 (Folder 15)
    - Holmes, Martin, 1988-1989 (Folder 16)
    - Homan, Roger, 1985-1986 (Folder 17)
    - Hoos, Ida, 1980-1981 (Folder 18)
    - Horam, John, 1981-1984 (Folder 19)
    - Horrobin, David, 1986-1987 (Folder 20)
    - Hoskyns, John, 1981-1984 (Folder 21)
    - Howarth, Richard, 1979-1991 (Folder 22)
    - Howe, Geoffrey, Sir, 1981-1983 (Folder 23)
    - Howell, David, 1983-1988 (Folder 24)
    - Howell, Gareth, 1984-1985 (Folder 25)
    - Humphrey, Patrick, 1983-1984 (Folder 26)
    - Hutchinson, T. W., 1979-1988 (Folder 27)
    - Hutt, W. H., 1980-1985 (Folder 28)
    - Jackman, Richard, 1981-1985 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Jackson, Peter, 1980-1982 (Folder 2)
    - James, Michael, 1989-1990 (Folder 3)
    - Jarman, Howard, 1983-1984 (Folder 4)
    - Jasay, Anthony de, 1986-1991 (Folder 5)
    - Jay, Antony, 1983-1984 (Folder 6)
    - Jenkins, D. E., 1988-1989 (Folder 7)
    - Jewkes, John, 1979-1980 (Folder 8)
    - Johns, Peter, 1990-1991 (Folder 9)
    - Jones, Silvan, 1991 (Folder 10)
    - Juby, Bernard, 1981-1985 (Folder 11)
    - Judge, Kenneth, 1981-1986 (Folder 12)
    - Jump, Nigel, 1980-1982 (Folder 13)
    - Kagalovsky, K., 1989-1990 (Folder 14)
    - Kasper, Wolfgang, 1985-1990 (Folder 15)
    - Kasun, Jacqueline, 1989-1990 (Folder 16)
    - Keeley, Phil, 1982 (Folder 17)
    - Kellner, Peter, 1985 (Folder 18)
    - Klein, Rudolf, 1982-1985 (Folder 19)
    - Knag, Sigmund, 1985-1986 (Folder 20)
    - Knox, Frank, 1986 (Folder 21)
    - Knutsen, John, 1991 (Folder 22)
    - Kowalski, John, 1989-1990 (Folder 23)
    - Krosnjö, Tom, 1985-1986 (Folder 24)
    - Laidler, David, 1983 (Folder 25)
    - Lait, June, 1980 (Folder 26)
    - Lal, Deepak, 1989-1991 (Folder 27)
    - Law, Richard, 1983 (Folder 28)
    - Layard, Richard, 1982-1991 (Folder 29)
    - Leaper, R. A. B., 1985 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Leddin, Anthony, 1991 (Folder 2)
    - Lee, Dwight, 1989-1990 (Folder 3)
    - Lee, Kwan Yew, 1980-1983 (Folder 4)
    - Lees, Dennis, 1979-1983 (Folder 5)
    - Le Grand, Julian, 1982-1986 (Folder 6)
    - Lejeune, Anthony, 1990-1991 (Folder 7)
    - Lepage, Henri, 1981-1984 (Folder 8)
    - Letwin, Oliver, 1989-1990 (Folder 9)
    - Leube, Kurt, 1983-1986 (Folder 10)
    - Levacic, Rosalind, 1982-1986 (Folder 11)
    - Lewis, John Perry, 1985-1986 (Folder 12)
    - Lewis, Russell, 1983-1991 (Folder 13)
    - Liggio, Leonard, 1989-1990 (Folder 14)
    - Lilley, Peter, 1987-1990 (Folder 15)
    - Lindsay, Cotton, 1984-1986 (Folder 16)
    - Lister, Ian, 1986-1987 (Folder 17)
    - Liston, David, 1989 (Folder 18)
    - Llewellyn, David, 1990-1991 (Folder 19)
    - Loasby, Brian, 1983-1991 (Folder 20)
    - Loder, Timothy, 1985-1986 (Folder 21)
    - Lombard, J. A., 1982-1986 (Folder 22)
    - Long, G. E., 1984-1986 (Folder 23)
    - Longman Group Limited
      - 1982-1983 (Folder 24)
      - 1984
        - January-June (Folder 25)
        - July-December (Folder 26)
      - 1985 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Lord, Rodney, 1982-1991 (Folder 2)
    - Louw, Frances Kendall and Leon, 1982-1988 (Folder 3)
    - Lund, Tim, 1988 (Folder 4)
    - Lydall, Harold, 1989-1990 (Folder 5)
    - Lynn, Richard, 1979-1989 (Folder 6)
    - McAlpine, Kenneth, 1982-1985 (Folder 7)
    - McChesney, Fred, 1986-1987 (Folder 8)
    - McCloskey, Donald, 1987-1991 (Folder 9)
    - McCord, Norman, 1979-1985 (Folder 10)
    - McCrostie, Michael, 1981-1985 (Folder 11)
    - McEnery, J. H., 1982-1984 (Folder 12)
    - McGee, Robert, 1989-1990 (Folder 13)
    - Machan, Tibor, 1988-1991 (Folder 14)
    - McKenzie, Richard, 1989-1991 (Folder 15)
    - McNutt, Patrick, 1990-1991 (Folder 16)
    - Manis, Kosta, 1991 (Folder 17)
    - Marsland, David, 1980-1990 (Folder 18)
    - Martino, Antonio, 1985-1987 (Folder 19)
    - Massey, Pat, 1990 (Folder 20)
    - Mastbergen, Breffni van, 1988-1990 (Folder 21)
    - Mathur, R. B., 1990-1991 (Folder 22)
    - Matthews, Kent, 1986-1990 (Folder 23)
    - Maunder, Peter, 1984-1990 (Folder 24)
    - Maycock, Richard, 1990-1991 (Folder 25)
    - Meakin, Christopher, 1987-1988 (Folder 26)
    - Melnyk, Andrew, 1987-1989 (Folder 27)
    - Meyer, Bruce, 1987-1988 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - MFL Publications Ltd., 1985-1987 (Folder 2)
    - Miller, Robert, 1987 (Folder 3)
    - Minford, Patrick, 1985-1991 (Folder 4)
    - Mobbs, Tim, 1983-1984 (Folder 5)
    - Moghadam, Raza, 1988-1991 (Folder 6)
    - Moldofsky, Naomi, 1984-1985 (Folder 7)
    - Molsberger, Josef, 1984-1985 (Folder 8)
    - Morgan, David, 1983-1985 (Folder 9)
    - Moslet, Anne Beth, 1983-1984 (Folder 10)
    - Murley, Reginald, Sir, 1985-1986 (Folder 11)
    - Myddelton, D. R., 1979-1988 (Folder 12)
    - Myers, Danny, 1982 (Folder 13)
    - Nagy, Tibor, 1984 (Folder 14)
    - Nataf, Philippe, 1985 (Folder 15)
    - Neal, Leonard, 1984 (Folder 16)
    - Newsom, Christopher, 1980 (Folder 17)
    - Niskanen, William, 1980-1981 (Folder 18)
    - Noar, Michael, 1984 (Folder 19)
    - Nobay, R. A., 1980-1984 (Folder 20)
    - North, Maurice, 1980-1986 (Folder 21)
    - Notten, Michael van, 1981-1984 (Folder 22)
    - Nove, Alec, 1983-1989 (Folder 23)
    - Odling, Michael, 1982-1984 (Folder 24)
    - O'Keefe, Dennis, 1982-1988 (Folder 25)
    - O'Mahony, David, 1981-1988 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Ording, Ebbe, 1985-1986 (Folder 2)
    - Osterfeld, David, 1988-1991 (Folder 3)
    - Owen, David, 1983 (Folder 4)
    - Oxford University Press, 1992-1993 (Folder 5)
    - Pai, M. R., 1987-1989 (Folder 6)
    - Palda, Kristian, 1983-1984 (Folder 7)
    - Paldam, Martin, 1982-1983 (Folder 8)
    - Papps, Ivy, 1979-1991 (Folder 9)
    - Parker, David, 1988-1991 (Folder 10)
    - Parker, Hermione, 1982-1990 (Folder 11)
    - Parkinson, Ann and Cecil, 1984-1986 (Folder 12)